Anantha Raju C Software Engineer

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/anantharajuc 🔭 https://anantharajuc.github.io/blog/

🌎 https://github.com/AnanthaRajuC 📑 https://stackoverflow.com/users/3711562/anantha-raju-c

Profile

Java (Spring Boot) developer with 6+ years of professional experience working on back-end systems in an enterprise (B2B2C) environment building Web Applications for products in Customer Engagement domain (Mar-Tech/Ad-Tech).

Proficient in integration of **RESTful Web Services** right from *Requirement Specification, Planning, Designing, Implementation, Configuration, Testing & Documentation* untill *Closure* based on *Agile Methodologies*.

Key Skills

Web Application (Backend) Design & Development, Project Management, Agile SDLC.

Technical Skills

Spring Boot (Spring Data JPA, Spring Data MongoDB, Spring Web, Spring Security, H2 Database, Java Mail Sender, Lombok, Thymeleaf, Flyway Migration, Swagger UI),

Java 8, RESTful Web Services (HATEOAS), Testing (Unit & Integration Testing via. JUnit, AssertJ, Mockito), AWS (RDS, Elastic Beanstalk, DynamoDB, IAM), Git (GitFlow Workflow, Feature Branch Workflow), NoSQL (MongoDB), MySQL, Data Structures, Maven, Docker, Linux, HTML

Certifications

LinkedIn Learning ☑, Google Cloud Platform and Amazon Web Services ☑ (Qwiklabs), IBM Marketing Cloud ☑, Adobe Marketing Cloud ☑

Education

Visvesvaraya Technological University, (VTU) ☑

Bangalore, India

- Masters of Technology (M. Tech), Computer Science Engineering
- Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science Engineering

Key Result Areas Across Projects

- Provided overall leadership to the entire team including managing deliverables of other functional team leaders.
- Analyzed & designed architecture definition, design patterns and solutions for the project; designed & selected appropriate technologies for development approach.
- Monitored development activities and conducted timely risk assessment & mitigation; managed and provided technical & process level guidance/support to the project team.
- Prioritized project initiation and reporting w.r.t. development projects to senior management and stakeholders.
- Gathered requirements from the client, prepared estimates & requirement specification, created prototypes and developed technical specification documents along with team members.

Professional Experience - Summary

Software Engineer, Customer Centria

10/2015 - present | Bangalore, India

- Responsible for integrating Customer Centria's flagship Marketing Campaign Product Suite **CC Engage** with several communication channels of other enterprise grade Mar-Tech solutions.
- Responsible for developing **Proof-of-Concept** Product and Solution Implementation for prospects as per their business use-cases during **Pre-sales** & **Implementation** cycle.
- Significant experience in working with customers, project managers and technical teams for securing & executing concurrent projects.
- Conducted multiple **Online/Off-line Training Sessions** on the Mar-Tech Industry and the in-house Marketing Automation and Data Management Platform product based on previous client use cases to several recruits.

Product - CC Engage

Omnichannel Marketing Automation Platform

2016 - present | Bangalore, India

CC Engage is an Enterprise Grade Digital Marketing Product Suite.

- Integrated Core features of (Silverpop/IBM Watson Campaign ☑ /acoustic ☑) with CC Engage via RESTful web services.
- Involved in development & maintenance of product features along with custom feature development for clients during the implementation cycle.
- Integrated multiple communications channels (SMS, Email, IVR, Social) from multiple vendors via REST Web Services Facebook Messenger ☑, Whatsapp Business Solution ☑, mapp/Teradata ☑, Ozonetel ☑, Karix ☑, Alot Solutions ☑, Twilio ☑, SendGrid ☑.
- Responsible for developing the back-end service for Mobile Push Notification (**Android**) as a communication channel via **Goolge Cloud Messenger** (GCM). Migrated the aforementioned Mobile Push Notification service from GCM to **Firebase Cloud Messaging** (FCM).

Project - Deltin (Delta Corp Limited)

CC Engage Platform, (Data & Campaign Management)

2017 - present | India

Deltin is a listed company in gaming and hospitality industry.

- Accountable for the off-site deployment (**On-premise**) and eventual migration to **Cloud** (AWS) of Omnichannel Marketing Automation tool with multiple data sources.
- Responsible for overall project from gathering the requirements to implementing the use cases, RESTful
 Web Service Integration with Multiple Email (Juxtmail, MAPP/Teradata) and SMS (Ozonetel) Gateway
 vendors.
- Designed an algorithm and developed the code to automate the Batch Processing of Email & SMS marketing campaign's as per business requirement.
- Completed **Documentation, Bug Fixes** and **Test Cases** on the features developed.

Pre-Sales Engineering

CC Engage Platform, (Data & Campaign Management)

10/2015 - present

- Pre-Sales Engineering experience of Enterprise Data Management & Marketing Automation Solution across industry verticals such as **BFSI**, **Retail**, **Telecom**, **Airlines**.
- Study the prospect, find the product fit by identifying relevant use-cases and finally design, develop the same using CC Engage
- Lead a team for the development of Prospects' Business Use Cases into solution implementation during the Proof-of-Concept development

Anantha Raju C anantharajuc@gmail.com 2/3

Open Source

Spring Boot Application Template,

08/2018 - present

65 Stars, 195 Forks on GitHub 🛚

This repository contains a recipe/scaffolding for bootstrapping a Web Application with the features & Technology stack listed below. Delete the sample code (or keep it.) and add your own, you're good to go.

Essentially it's a simple **on-demand application back-end** for rapid-prototyping.

Features: Internationalization, API Rate Limiting, RBAC with JWT, JPA Auditing, HTTPS, Continuous Integration

Tech Stack: Spring Boot, Spring Security, Swagger UI, Bootstrap, Thymeleaf, MySQL, Docker, dockerhub, Travis CI

Blog

https://anantharajuc.github.io/

2015 - present

A Personal blog on Technology where i capture my experience with new tools, platforms and services.

All posts follow a minimalist tutorial-style format with images wherever necessary to document a concept/process for myself and acts as a source of quick reference.

Publications

Resource Management by Virtual Machine Migration in

12/2015

Cloud Computing, *International Journal of Computer Science and Mobile Computing* ☑

- Features include improvement of Power utilization in a Simulated Data center, over existing systems.
- Developed using Java and *CloudSim* simulation Framework.